James Mullineaux

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Main Contractor QS, PQS

& Employer's Agent

Cost Planning

Tendering

Procurement

Cost Management

Contract Administration

Change Control

Subcontractor Management

Client Management

I am a dynamic, pragmatic and forward thinking Quantity Surveyor who is well versed in contract knowledge, procurement and cost management. I possess multi-sector versatility demonstrated by a successful record of task management, problem solving and project delivery for main contractors, multidisciplinary consultancies and clients.

Having acquired experience across a wide-ranging portfolio of projects and different forms of construction contracts, I aim to lead by example, instil trust and add value to any project I am involved with.

My driven nature enables me to work methodically with an accurate eye for detail continually delivering a professional service and value for money.

CAREER HISTORY

Llama Group Limited, Cheshire

Senior Quantity Surveyor April 2017 – Present

Main Projects to date Include:

- The Spinney Knutsford Major Refurbishment, Extension and Fit Out Works of High End Residential Property - Value £3.25m
- The Whitehouse, Acton Bridge, Cheshire Major extension and remodelling of large country residence and external works Value £2.5m
- The Grange, Bridgnorth, Shropshire. Major fit out and remodelling of Grade II Listed Property complete with Extension works Value £3m
- Ashbrook Barn, Abbotts Bromley, Staffordshire. Complete New build of High End fine country residence - Value £2.25m

Primary Roles / Responsibilities

- Preparation of initial construction Budgets for client agreement
- Preparation of Value Engineering exercises as required
- Preparation of JCT Design and Build contracts
- Preparation of Subcontract packages
- Appointment and administration of subcontractors on site
- Management of Change Order and Variation Accounts
- Interim Valuation and Final Account Agreement

Thomas Barnes (Plc), Bury

Project Quantity Surveyor April 2015 –Dec 2016

Main Projects Include:

- Kendal College Extension and refurbishment Value £1.25m
- Higher Broughton Health Centre New Build Value £4.75m

Primary Roles / Responsibilities:

- Tendering, procurement and contract administration
- Preparation, and formal issue of JCT98/05 and NEC3 contracts
- Co-ordination and chairing of design team and progress meetings
- Cost management / assessment of main contractor valuations
- Financial reporting / preparing, negotiating and agreeing final accounts
- Assisting Senior Project Managers on site.

SECTOR EXPERIENCE

High-End Residential

Private Residential

Affordable Housing

Multi Storey Residential

Refurbishment

Commercial/Industrial

Infrastructure

Heritage/Listed Property

DLP Ltd, Manchester

Senior Quantity Surveyor May 2013 – April 2015

Main Projects Include:

- Salford City Council Void Property Grant Schemes
- Various North West Local Councils Disabled Adaptation Schemes

Primary Roles / Responsibilities

- Attending site to assess and schedule out required works
- Liaising with client and Local Authority on works required
- Pricing up works for in house labour
- Preparing subcontract packages for M&E works
- · Agreeing variations and Final accounts with Local Authority
- Financial reporting
- All this was fast paced work of short contract duration

Richmond Square Construction, Isle of Man

Project Quantity Surveyor Sep 2010 – Oct 2012

Main Projects Include:

- Oak Hill Mansion, New Build Country Estate Value £16m+
- Thie Ny Strooan New Build residential dwelling Value £9m+
- The Mallards, New Build Country Estate Value £18m+

Primary Roles / Responsibilities:

- Tendering and procurement of specialist bespoke materials
- Preparing subcontract packages for M&E works
- Management of Change Order and Variation Accounts
- Interim Valuation and Final Account Agreement
- Financial reporting

Dandara Group, Isle of Man

Project Quantity Surveyor Sep 2003 – Aug 2010

Main Projects Include:

- Multi Storey Apartment Developments Value up to £10m
- New Housing Developments Up to 400 units
- New Build Commercial Units Up to 50,000sq ft

Primary Roles / Responsibilities:

- Appointment of specialist sub-contractors
- Cost management / assessment of sub-contractor valuations
- Site visits / inspections carried out for commercial meetings
- Financial reporting / preparing, negotiating and agreeing Final Accounts

Sep 1988 - Jun 1996

CONTACT

PERSONAL

Ambitious

Enthusiastic

Pragmatic

Practical Problem Solver

Full UK Driving Licence

PROFESSIONAL

Ms Excel

MS Word

Ms Project

Telephone:

+44 (0) 7434 975 804

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

University College Salford

BSc (RICS accredited) Quantity Surveying

- HNC Building Studies
- ONC Building Sudies

Email:

mullineauxjames @gmail.com

Location:

Astley, Manchester. M29.